

Gianvito CALABRESE

Avezzano/Italy | (+39)3349499532
gcalabrese296@gmail.com
github | in linkedin

SUMMARY

I was born the 3rd of September 1992 in Bari where I spent my first 26 years. Afterwards I have settled in various places in Italy, everytime moved by the aim of better growth opportunities. I am a dedicated, creative and proactive physicist with three years job experience in the semiconductor related applications. I have designed novel devices and carried out experiments as academic technologist. I possess excellent analytical and communications skills and this allowed me to successfully move from university to industry in the role of yield enhancement engineer. I have spent my life always looking for opportunities to utilize my technical skills in a challenging working environment and become a valuable asset to the organization I work for.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BARI 2011-2014

B.S IN PHYSICS

• Analog electronics, NIM modules, Theoretical Physics, Advanced Math.

University of Bari 2014-2017

M.S in Applied and Condensed Matter Physics

· Material properties, Optoelectronic, Optical instruments, Semiconductors, Lasers, Digital electronics.

EXPERIENCE ___

IT CONSULTANT

Jen 2018 - Oct 2018 (Milan/Italy)

EXPRIVIA S.P.A.

PHD STUDENT IN PHYSICS ENGINEERING

Nov 2018 - Dec 2019 (Como/Italy)

L-NESS POLITECNICO DI MILANO

- Design and Fabrication of Graphene FET via eBeam Lithography.
- Device Electrical Measurements and Characterization.

EXT MANUFACTURING YIELD ENGINEER

Jen 2020 - on going (Avezzano/Italy)

ONSEMI

- Statistical analysis of wafer level probe data for yield enhancement purpose.
- Coordination and cooperation of the manufacturing process improvement activities at supplier level.
- Support on the production material management operations.
- · Basics of Product Engineering.

SKILLS ___

SOFTWARE *Experienced:* Spotfire Exensio | JMP *Familiar:* Orcad

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE Familiar: Python | SQL | bash Occasional: C/C++ | Mathematica

OPERATING SYSTEM Windows | GNU/Linux

LANGUAGES *Native:* Italian *Fluent:* English (*)

DRIVING LICENSE B

EXTRA

• (*) Graded as B2 - based on TOEIC, Listening and Reading Test (27/09/2018)

December 11, 2021 / source code